{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Which one of the following represents an activity", "opta": "excavation for foundation", "optb": "curing of concrete", "optc": "setting of question paper", "optd": "preparation of breakfast", "opte": "all the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pick up the incorrect statement from the following:", "opta": "An activity of a project is denoted by an arrow on the net work", "optb": "The tail of the arrow indicates the start of the activity", "optc": "The head of the arrow indicates the end of the activity", "optd": "The arrows are drawn to scale from left to right", "opte": "Each activity consumes a given time.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The technique for establishing and maintaining priorities among the various jobs of a project, is known", "opta": "Event flow scheduling technique", "optb": "Critical ratio scheduling", "optc": "Slotting technique for scheduling", "optd": "Short interval scheduling.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Mile Stone charts were invented in the year of", "opta": "1910", "optb": "1920", "optc": "1930", "optd": "1940", "opte": "1950", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Frederick W. Taylor introduced a system of working known as", "opta": "line organisation", "optb": "line and staff organisation", "optc": "functional organisation", "optd": "effective organisation.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If to, tp and tm are the optimistic, pessimistic and most likely time estimates of an activity respectively, the expected time t of the activity will be", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "opte": "", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In the given figure, the network of a project represents", "opta": "activity of an excavation of a footing", "optb": "activity of an excavation which starts at event No. 1 and ends at even No. 2", "optc": "activity of excavation which takes 8 units of time", "optd": "none of these.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pick up the PERT event from the following:", "opta": "Digging of foundation started", "optb": "Digging of foundation completed", "optc": "Laying of concrete started", "optd": "Laying of concrete completed", "opte": "All the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If D is the duration, ES and EF are the earliest start and finish, LS and LF are latest start and latest finish time, then the following relation holds good", "opta": "EF = ES + D", "optb": "LS = LF - D", "optc": "LF = LS + D", "optd": "D = EF - ES", "opte": "all the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Final technical authority of a project lies with", "opta": "Assistant Engineer", "optb": "Executive Engineer", "optc": "Superintending Engineer", "optd": "Chief Engineer.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The performance of a specific task in CPM, is known", "opta": "Dummy", "optb": "Event", "optc": "Activity", "optd": "Contract.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pick up the correct statement from the following:", "opta": "The float may be positive, zero or negative", "optb": "If the float is positive and the activity is delayed by a period equal to its total float, the completion of project is not delayed", "optc": "If the float of an activity is negative, delay in its performance is bound to delay the completion of project", "optd": "If the float of an activity is zero, the activity is critical and any delay in its performance will delay the whole project", "opte": "All the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A Milestone chart", "opta": "shows the interdependencies of various jobs", "optb": "depicts the delay of jobs, if any", "optc": "points outgoing ahead of schedule of jobs, if any", "optd": "none of these.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Completion of an activity on CPM network diagram, is generally known", "opta": "Event", "optb": "Node", "optc": "Connector", "optd": "All the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A dummy activity", "opta": "is artificially introduced", "optb": "is represented by a dotted line", "optc": "does not consume time", "optd": "all the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Military organisation is known as", "opta": "line organisation", "optb": "line and staff organisation", "optc": "functional organisation", "optd": "none of these.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pick up the incorrect statement from the following:", "opta": "The activity is the time consuming part of a project", "optb": "The beginning and end of a job, are called events", "optc": "The activity which consumes maximum time, is called a node", "optd": "Logically and sequentially connected activities and events form a network", "opte": "None of these.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Various activities of a project, are shown on bar charts by", "opta": "vertical lines", "optb": "horizontal lines", "optc": "dots", "optd": "crosses.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Time and progress chart of a construction, is also known as", "opta": "Bar chart", "optb": "Gantt chart", "optc": "Modified Mile stone chart", "optd": "Critical path method chart", "opte": "All the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Critical Path Net Work helps an engineer", "opta": "to concentrate his attention on critical activities", "optb": "to divert the resources from non-critical advanced activities to critical activities", "optc": "to be cautious for avoiding any delay in the critical activities to avoid delay of the whole project", "optd": "all the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If a is the optimistic time, b is the pessimistic time and m is most likely time of an activity, the expected time of the activity, is", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The time by which activity completion time can be delayed without affecting the start of succeeding activities, is known as", "opta": "duration", "optb": "total flat", "optc": "free float", "optd": "interfering float.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The artificial activity which indicates that an activity following it, cannot be started unless the preceding activity is complete, is known as", "opta": "event", "optb": "free float", "optc": "dummy", "optd": "constant", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Henry Gantt developed Bar charts for planning and scheduling of projects in", "opta": "1880", "optb": "1900", "optc": "1920", "optd": "1940", "opte": "1950", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The most popular type of organisation used for Civil Engineering Constructions, is", "opta": "line organisation", "optb": "line and staff organisation", "optc": "functional organisation", "optd": "effective organisation.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The difference between the time avail-to do a job and the time required to do the job, is known as", "opta": "event", "optb": "float", "optc": "duration", "optd": "constraint.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The object of technical planning, is", "opta": "preparation of specifications", "optb": "preparation of estimates", "optc": "initiating the procurement action of resources", "optd": "taking remedial action for likely bottleneck in the execution", "opte": "all the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The salient feature of functional organisation is", "opta": "strict adherence to specifications", "optb": "separation of planning and design part", "optc": "each individual maintains functional efficiency", "optd": "work is properly planned and distributed", "opte": "all the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Critical path method", "opta": "is an improvement upon bar chart method", "optb": "provides a realistic approach to daily problems", "optc": "avoids delays which are very common in bar charts", "optd": "was invented by Morgan R. Walker of Dupot and James E. Kalley or Remington U.S.A. in 1957", "opte": "All the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "CPM is", "opta": "synthesising in concepts", "optb": "is built of activities oriented programme", "optc": "is based on time estimate", "optd": "is used for repetitive works", "opte": "all the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Critical path lies along the activities having total float", "opta": "positive", "optb": "negative", "optc": "zero", "optd": "same.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Construction team means", "opta": "an engineer", "optb": "an architect", "optc": "an owner", "optd": "a contractor", "opte": "all the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pick up the correct network for the activities of pouring concrete, erection of form work, removal of form work and curing of concrete from the following:", "opta": "1. Pouring of Concrete  2. Erection of form work 3. Curing of concrete 4. Removal of form work", "optb": "1. Erection of form work 2. Pouring of concrete 3. Curing of concrete 4. Removal of form work", "optc": "1. Removal of form work  2. Erection of form work 3. Pouring of concrete 4. Curing of concrete", "optd": "1. Pouring of concrete 2. Curing of concrete 3. Erection of form work 4. Removal of form work", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A construction schedule is prepared after collecting", "opta": "number of operations", "optb": "output of labour", "optc": "output of machinery", "optd": "quantity of various items", "opte": "all the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Site order book is used for recording", "opta": "instructions by the executive engineers", "optb": "construction measurements", "optc": "issue of store equipments", "optd": "names of the casual labour.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An Executive Engineer may have powers upto", "opta": "Rs. 25,000", "optb": "Rs. 50,000", "optc": "Rs. 100,000", "optd": "Rs. 200,000", "opte": "Rs. 500,000", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The main principle of an organisation, is", "opta": "unity of command", "optb": "cohegency", "optc": "effective control at all levels", "optd": "delegation of authority", "opte": "all the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The estimated time required to perform an activity, is known as", "opta": "event", "optb": "dummy", "optc": "duration", "optd": "float.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A CPM family includes", "opta": "CPA (Critical Path Analysis)", "optb": "CPP (Critical Path Plotted)", "optc": "MCE (Minimum Cost Expenditure)", "optd": "CPS (Critical Path Scheduling)", "opte": "All the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The time which results in the leasi, possible construction cost of an activity, is known", "opta": "normal time", "optb": "slow time", "optc": "crash time", "optd": "standard time.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If the total float and duration of an activity are 5 and 10 days respectively, the particular activity can be", "opta": "started 5 days later", "optb": "completed 5 days later", "optc": "performed at slower rate in 15 days", "optd": "all the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Works costing less than Rs. 20,000 are treated as", "opta": "projects", "optb": "major projects", "optc": "minor projects", "optd": "all the above.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A critical ratio scheduling", "opta": "establishes the relative priorities among various activities on a common basis", "optb": "determines the status of each activity", "optc": "adjusts automatically changes in activity progress", "optd": "is a dynamic system", "opte": "none of these.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Bar charts are suitable for", "opta": "minor works", "optb": "major works", "optc": "large projects", "optd": "all the Above.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The first method invented for planning projects, was", "opta": "Bar chart method", "optb": "Milestone chart", "optc": "Critical path method (CPM)", "optd": "Programme Evaluation and Review Technique (PERT)", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If TL is the latest allowable event occurrence time, total activity slack(s), is equal to", "opta": "LST-EST", "optb": "LFT-EFT", "optc": "TL-EFT", "optd": "all the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The Overall in-charge of an organisation at the site responsible for the execution of the works, is", "opta": "Executive Engineer", "optb": "Engineer", "optc": "Junior Engineer", "optd": "Sub overseer", "opte": "Assistant Engineer.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Modular co-ordination of construction means proper", "opta": "planning", "optb": "designing", "optc": "execution", "optd": "all the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pick up the correct statement from the following:", "opta": "CPM analysis is activity oriented", "optb": "PERT analysis is event oriented", "optc": "CPM does not make any allowance for the uncertainties in the duration of time", "optd": "In CPM, the time is related to cost", "opte": "All the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}